whois-search.com 2019-03-05

# Whois Search - Domain Name Search | Whois lookup | Availability Checker

Last updated: 24th May 2018 

[Whois-Search.com](http://www.whois-search.com/) operates under data protection laws of the United Kingdom (UK) including the General Data Protection Regulation ([GDPR](https://whois-search.com/pages/GDPR)) (EU) 2016/679. This privacy policy describes what personal information we collect and how we will use it. It closely follows guidance provided by the UK data protection authority, the Information Commissioner. 

[Whois-Register.com](http://www.whois-register.com/) collects personal information when you register with us or register a domain name with us. We will use this information to provide the services requested, maintain domain name registration records including publication of registrant data on the web as part of the WHOIS service and, if you agree, to send you expiry information. We will not share your information for marketing purposes with third party companies. 

**In more detail:**

**What information do we collect about you and your customers?**

We collect information about you when you sign up for our services, including registration of a domain name, hosting or related services. The information includes name, address and other contact details, order history, and a record of the services that you have purchased. Website usage information is collected through Cookies and Google Analytics (anonymized IP Addresses). 

We do not store credit card details, nor do we share customer details with any third parties. 

We do not store domain name whois information from other registrars or registries. 

**How will we use the information about you?**

We collect information about you and your customers so that we can process your orders such as domain name registration, renewal and maintenance, and to manage your account. We will share your information with our reseller provider Enom LLC who share it with domain name registries, ICANN and Enom's appointed data escrow providers as part of domain name registration, maintenance and renewal. It is necessary for us to process your information in these ways, so that we are able to provide the services to you. If you agree, we can use the information about you to email you about other products and services we think may be of interest to you. By agreeing to our terms of service, you agree to this processing, and you may withdraw that consent at any time by contacting us in writing or by email. 

**The WHOIS service**

[Whois-Search.com](http://www.whois-search.com/) does not store or control whois information displayed on our website. Every domain name registry is queried live and we are not responsible for live whois results. 

[Whois-Register.com](http://www.whois-register.com/) will publish your contact information on the web (throughout the world) as part of the WHOIS service. We have a legal obligation to provide the WHOIS service as part of our accreditation agreement with ICANN and individual country domain name registries (ccTLDs). 

The ICANN policy in relation to WHOIS is evolving in response to changes in European privacy laws. We will continue to monitor developments and update our privacy policy accordingly. 

You currently have three options in relation to WHOIS: 

1\. The current default arrangement is that the WHOIS output for your domain name will not publish your name, key elements of your postal address, telephone or fax numbers as part of the public WHOIS. The following details will be published: county and country, and we will provide a proxy email or contact form instead of your email address. 

2\. You have the option of having your full contact details (including contact name, business/organisation name, postal address, email address, telephone, fax) published along with technical details about your domain name as part of the WHOIS service, 

3\. You may choose to have privacy/proxy protection which will hide all your contact details behind those of a proxy. You are free to switch off that privacy/proxy protection at any time, and our privacy proxy policy explains the circumstances in which we will remove that privacy/proxy protection and/or share your contact information with law enforcement or third parties with a legitimate interest in obtaining your information. 

We will not share your information for marketing purposes with companies outside our group of companies or our reseller provider Enom LLC. 

In processing your orders we may send your details to and use information from credit reference agencies, fraud prevention agencies and ICANN (including ICANN compliance). 

**Access to your information and correction**

You have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please email or write to us at the following address. We may make a small charge for this service. 

We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date, and we are required to keep domain name registration information accurate and up to date under the terms of our reseller agreement with Enom LLC. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate. 

**Retention period and your right of deletion**

While you are an active customer (ie you have active or recently expired domain name registrations and related services with us), it is necessary for us to retain your data to fulfil the contract, or as a result of legal obligations to ICANN and other ccTLD registries.   
We regularly delete (at least once a year) historic data, including domain name records, relating to our customers, but we will retain your name and contact details as part of our internal marketing records so that we can contact you with market offerings that we believe will be of interest to you, if you agree. 

We will delete your data if you send us a written request by email or letter. We will not be able to delete data that is necessary for the fulfilment of your contract with us, nor will we be able to delete data that we have a legal obligation to retain. 

**Cookies**

Cookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of the website, to maintain information in webforms while you are filling them in, and to compile statistical reports on website activity. 

For further information, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org]. You can set your browser not to accept cookies and the above website tells you how to remove cookies from your browser. However, you should be aware that some website features may not function as a result. 

**Other websites**

Our website contains links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to our website so when you link to another website you should read their privacy policy. 

**Changes to our privacy policy**

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this webpage. The date when this policy was last updated is at the top of the web page. 

**How to contact us**

When you give us your personal data - for example, when you become our customer, or use our website - we are the data controller of that data. Our full contact details are below: 

By email support [at] whois-search.com 

Or write to us at: 

Whois-Search.com  
C/O Netistrar Limited  
Repton House  
Bretby Business Park  
Ashby Road  
Burton Upon Trent  
DE15 0YZ  
United Kingdom 

**Your right to make a complaint**

If you would like to make a complaint about the way we process your personal data, we hope that you will contact us using the details above, and we will endeavour to resolve your complaint. 

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the UK Information Commissioner.
